<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hector's Blog</title>
    <description>Hector's tech blog</description>
    <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hectron.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Using IFTTT to leverage the invisble hand</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tl-dr&quot;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set up a custom recipe in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; to alert you
whenever a new listing is available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://craigslist.org/&quot;&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/recipes/229-send-yourself-emails-for-new-craigslist-postings-from-any-search-you-re-interested-in&quot;&gt;this website loaded in the
background&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;http://craigslist.org/&quot;&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt;, perform a search, copy the URL from
the address bar after the search has been performed, paste it into the search
URL box in the IFTTT, enter in your e-mail, and make the recipe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-background&quot;&gt;A little background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing my readers should know is that I’m a stan of music – all variety of
music. This is likely because I consider myself a hobbiest musician. As a
result, I suffer from what other musicians call &lt;strong&gt;GAS&lt;/strong&gt; (not necessarily the
result of dietary choices). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GAS&lt;/strong&gt; is known in the musician’s community as
&lt;strong&gt;Gear Acquisition Syndrome&lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;GAS&lt;/strong&gt; means that you love collection gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voxshowroom.com/uk/amp/ad30.html&quot;&gt;Vox AD30VT&lt;/a&gt;, a
small amp that has a tube in the preamp. It was OK for small band practices,
but the clean volume was just not cutting it – I need more wattage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting my quest to purchase an amp, I decided that whatever amp I got
needed to have the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affordability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reliability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean headroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, I wanted a tube amp that was realible and affordable. I set a budget
of $500 USD and performed research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few searches, I came to the
conclusion that a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fender.com/guitar-amplifiers/vintage-pro-tube/blues-deluxe-reissue/product-223220.html&quot;&gt;Fender Blues
Deluxe&lt;/a&gt;
or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://peavey.com/products/index.cfm/item/801/118120/Classic%2030&quot;&gt;Peavey
Classic&lt;/a&gt;
would have to be the amp that I choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because these amps are just over my budget, enter Craigslist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leveraging-if-this-then-that-ifttt&quot;&gt;Leveraging If This Then That (IFTTT)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I thought about monitoring a search query and ensuring I was
up-to-date with the search queries, I thought about automating this using
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is that I would perform a search query,
and anytime a new result was returned, I would get notified ASAP so that I
could act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/recipes/229-send-yourself-emails-for-new-craigslist-postings-from-any-search-you-re-interested-in&quot;&gt;this following recipe to monitor Craigslist
changes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was perform the search query that I needed. After that, I
copied the URL from the search result and pasted it into the Craiglist box
within the recipe page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then entered an e-mail address and saved the recipe. After it was saved, I
went into My Recipes and ended up modifying it. I changed the subject of the 
e-mail to be &lt;code&gt;[CL Deal] Peavey Classic&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re reading this blog, then you know I’m a bit more… unique
than the average internet user. Therefore, I ended up creating three different
alerts. Each one using the same term, but with a different maximum price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allowed me to change the subject of the e-mail that will be sent to myself
to something like &lt;code&gt;[CL BUY THIS NOW] Peavey Classic&lt;/code&gt; or something of that
nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-not-use-craigslist-alerts&quot;&gt;Why not use Craigslist alerts?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie – I didn’t know Craigslist alerts existed. Knowing that
now, I realize that one benefit that you have by using IFTTT is that you have a
centralized location for all your queries. Additionally, IFTTT will alert you
whenever something goes wrong with the service/integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging web automation tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; is a great way
to look for deals or to get alerts (weather, movies, etc). Hopefully by
leveraging these automation tools, I could stop hawking websites during work
hours and just wait for the deals to come to me rather than the other way
around.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/03/28/ifttt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/03/28/ifttt/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rewriting Git history for fun and profit</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tl-dr&quot;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can appear like a competent programmer by rewriting your commit
history with the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git reset HEAD~n&lt;/code&gt; where n is the number of prior commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add --patch&lt;/code&gt; to select the changes you want to include in a commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me, then you are likely to make a lot of Git commits.
Your commits might address spacing issues in code, or renaming variables
only to rename them back. You might be forced to fix a bug in the
process of working on your feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find a lot of unrelated data in a commit, you might want to
consider rewriting your commit history. This good shows you how to
rewrite history assuming that your changes are the latest changes in the
branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I oppose rewriting history on your &lt;strong&gt;master&lt;/strong&gt; branch. This is
considered bad practice and is discouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developing-a-plan&quot;&gt;Developing a plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are going to rewrite your Git commit history, you need to
identify what the purpose of the rewrite is. Are you trying to group all
your changes to a test suite? Are you creating new database migrations?
Are you working on two different components that are unrelated?
&lt;em&gt;Identify what you want to accomplish&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this tutorial, we will suppose that I grouped a
commit where I modified an HTML page, along with tweak it’s CSS and
added some javascript functions. My desired goal is to group all the
changes I made to the HTML markup in one commit, group all the CSS
changes in another commit and group all the Javascript changes in their
own commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what my original commit looked like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;commit 23106d0d38bd5a774d61f4632839d6fb61f20c66 Author: Hector Rios
&amp;lt;my@email.com&amp;gt; Date:   Fri Feb 13 15:26:22 2015 -0600

    Updated my Contact page.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;breaking-the-bad&quot;&gt;Breaking (the) bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step you need to do is rollback the changes in that commit so
that we can split them up into individual commits. To do this, do the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git reset HEAD^&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will go back one commit and unstage your commit’s changes. So now,
you want to run the command &lt;code&gt;git add --patch&lt;/code&gt;. This will bring an
interactive prompt in which you can select whether or not to stage that
change. In our case, we want to include only the changes we made to the
&lt;code&gt;*.html&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we selected all the changes, we commit that change, and move on to
the next file. When we do this to our stylesheets and javascript files,
we will now have three commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty nifty right? How about if we wanted to group by feature? Let’s do
that instead now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;undoing-our-changes-and-grouping-by-feature&quot;&gt;Undoing our changes and grouping by feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we now have three commits of our theoretical HTML/CSS/JS pages, we
need to undo all three commits. I personally squash the commits and then
repeat the trick above. So the commands look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rebase -i HEAD~3 (Then squash them into one commit) 
git reset HEAD^ 
git add --patch (select the chunks that relate to your feature)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way you can combine the changes per feature and commit them
individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that you combine your commits into one, then undo the
changes so that they are all unstaged. You then strategically stage them
and commit them. This way, your git history is logical.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/rewriting-git-history/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/rewriting-git-history/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Nitrous.IO for Web Development</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tl-dr&quot;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create a very functional development environment on Nitrous that is
accessible from anywhere that has an internet connection. Unfortunately, this is
a flaw. Without a fast connection, Nitrious might not be very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologists are familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law&quot;&gt;Moore’s
Law&lt;/a&gt; which states that the number of
transistors doubles every two years. In turn, this affects our computeres and
phones by allowing us to have more processing power. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what happens when your processing power is so efficient that each hardware
upgrade is less enticing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I consolidate my hardware to optimize it for Software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developing-a-plan&quot;&gt;Developing a plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself using the terminal and Google Chrome a lot. I use Virtual
machines for doing development on Linux environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My desktop is a custom built gaming computer that is seriously over-powered and
ridiculously underused; I don’t really consume much media on my computer except
for light video watching on Netflix. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my media is stored in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;the cloud&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822236519&quot;&gt;2 TB Western Digital Hard
Drive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take inventory here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-life-gives-you-saas-you-take-it&quot;&gt;When life gives you SaaS, you take it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com&quot;&gt;plenty of websites&lt;/a&gt; out there that teach you
how to make use of many cloud services in creative ways. Seeing as how it’s
increasingly difficult to not be connected in online services, I decided to
&lt;strong&gt;endure&lt;/strong&gt; the cloud and try out &lt;a href=&quot;https://nitrous.io/&quot;&gt;Nitrous.IO&lt;/a&gt; to do my web
development from an online IDE. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-things-it-does-good&quot;&gt;The things it does good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrous offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nitrousio-web-app/kcbmakmdbnehgbakmgibcpjpafenmohd?hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Chrome
App&lt;/a&gt;
that is amazing if you log into Chrome. This allows you to have Nitrous
installed on any Chrome you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terminal it provides is a full-fledged Linux bash terminal, which means that
most of your favorite dotfiles can be implemented in the terminal. I was able to
set up a NodeJS server very quickly, and had a fully functional development
environment thanks to migrating my dotfiles to a Git repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not underestimate the ability to have a fully functional development
environment within minutes, that can be accessed from anywhere, on any kind of
machine. While this might be scary to some, it’s not nearly as bad as you’d
think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-things-it-does-bad&quot;&gt;The things it does bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nitrous can be slow at times, and it requires you to have a fast internet
connection. Without a fast internet connection, Nitrous can be slow and lag when
doing any text editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to set up an account on Nitrous might be another flaw for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nitrous.io/&quot;&gt;Nitrous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/&quot;&gt;LifeHacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/15/using-nitrous-io/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/15/using-nitrous-io/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up a blog</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tl-dr&quot;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnotander/pixyll&quot;&gt;Pixyll
theme&lt;/a&gt;, with all my posts living
within &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hectron/blog&quot;&gt;my blog’s GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in a strange time in technology. Voicing your opinion online has
never been easier. There are infinite resources to create a blog online,
many claiming to be the best or claim to provide a productive workflow.
How does one decide which to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-is-not-a-one-size-fit-all&quot;&gt;There is not a one-size-fit-all&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is true. Consider managing documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are productive by keeping everything in their desktop,
others are most productive by keeping everything on a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;, others keep everything in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot;&gt;private
repository&lt;/a&gt;. The truth of the matter is you need
to choose what’s best for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-settled-on-jekyll&quot;&gt;Why I settled on Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve been tossing around the idea of abandoning my desktop
environment.&lt;/em&gt; I currently use a custom built desktop computer which I
have not been able to game on. In an effort to take a more minimal
approach, I have started to back up a lot of my data into my GitHub. I
have over 3 TB of space in my desktop, of which &lt;em&gt;I personally&lt;/em&gt; use about
200 MB of, most of which is code I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like to write during my commute, so I would like a blog that can
be worked on offline and then uploaded when I feel like the content is
decent enough. I have been doing a lot of Javascript development lately,
and one platform that caught my eye is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;.
Ghost is a blogging platform that runs on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that I’m aiming to &lt;em&gt;simplify&lt;/em&gt; my life, I don’t want to
lose sight of my end goal (which is writing) by having to worry about
how to configure, host and maintain my system. Similarly, I don’t want
to have another place on the internet where my password is used, even if
I rely on password managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I always interact with my git repositories, I figured that
anything which could be maintained using Vim &amp;amp; Git is going to be a
winner. Enter Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-community&quot;&gt;The power of community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing which Jekyll has going for it is it’s extensive documentation
and community. It’s very extensible and can very easily be tweaked.
Combine it’s ability to be run on multiple environments along with
integrating with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and you have
a combination that’s hard to beat (at least if you’re a developer who is
unafraid of the terminal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnotander/pixyll&quot;&gt;Pixyll theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/setting-up-a-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/setting-up-a-blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
