<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hector&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Hector&#39;s tech blog</description>
    <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hectron.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up a blog</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tl-dr&quot;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnotander/pixyll&quot;&gt;Pixyll
theme&lt;/a&gt;, with all my posts living
within &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hectron/blog&quot;&gt;my blog’s GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in a strange time in technology. Voicing your opinion online has
never been easier. There are infinite resources to create a blog online,
many claiming to be the best or claim to provide a productive workflow.
How does one decide which to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-is-not-a-one-size-fit-all&quot;&gt;There is not a one-size-fit-all&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is true. Consider managing documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are productive by keeping everything in their desktop,
others are most productive by keeping everything on a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;, others keep everything in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot;&gt;private
repository&lt;/a&gt;. The truth of the matter is you need
to choose what’s best for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-settled-on-jekyll&quot;&gt;Why I settled on Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve been tossing around the idea of abandoning my desktop
environment.&lt;/em&gt; I currently use a custom built desktop computer which I
have not been able to game on. In an effort to take a more minimal
approach, I have started to back up a lot of my data into my GitHub. I
have over 3 TB of space in my desktop, of which &lt;em&gt;I personally&lt;/em&gt; use about
200 MB of, most of which is code I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like to write during my commute, so I would like a blog that can
be worked on offline and then uploaded when I feel like the content is
decent enough. I have been doing a lot of Javascript development lately,
and one platform that caught my eye is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;.
Ghost is a blogging platform that runs on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that I’m aiming to &lt;em&gt;simplify&lt;/em&gt; my life, I don’t want to
lose sight of my end goal (which is writing) by having to worry about
how to configure, host and maintain my system. Similarly, I don’t want
to have another place on the internet where my password is used, even if
I rely on password managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I always interact with my git repositories, I figured that
anything which could be maintained using Vim &amp;amp; Git is going to be a
winner. Enter Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-community&quot;&gt;The power of community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing which Jekyll has going for it is it’s extensive documentation
and community. It’s very extensible and can very easily be tweaked.
Combine it’s ability to be run on multiple environments along with
integrating with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and you have
a combination that’s hard to beat (at least if you’re a developer who is
unafraid of the terminal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnotander/pixyll&quot;&gt;Pixyll theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 10:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/setting-up-a-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hectron.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/setting-up-a-blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
